千半田さん　ずばり　怪盗十文字を撃退できますか
もちろん　そのつもりです
皆さんの…　皆さんのお力添えがあれば
必ず十文字さんを捕えられると思います
おー　強気ですねえ
では　次にお聞きしたいのは十文字の狙うものです
それなら用意してあります
古典部のアイテムは「校了原稿」です
校了原稿？
はい　古典部の文集「氷菓」の校了原稿です
あれ　減ってる
この文集も十文字事件に負けず劣らず興味深い内容なのですが
もしよろしければご一読ください
皆さんにも楽しんでいただけるとは思います
おー　それは気になりますね
ええ
皆さん　古典部の文集「氷菓」をよろしくお願いします
きっと気にいってもらえると思います
ところで　十文字さんをお迎えするんにあたって
古典部から皆さんにお願いがあります
ほ　お願いですか
はい
何しろ　部員は四名だけですので
監視の目が足りません
ですから　ぜひ皆さんに古典部に来てほしいんです
ありがとうございます
皆さんは頼りです
なるほど　人海戦術ですね
はい　皆さんのお力添えに期待してます
そう頼まれると弱いですね～
This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance to real persons, groups or events is purely coincidental.
それと　できたら文集のほうも…
So, Chitanda,
you're saying you can put a stop to the mysterious thief, Juumoji?
Yes, that's what we're trying to do!
買ってください…　ね
With everyone's...
さあ　最後の標的古典部は迎撃準備万端です
Radio broadcast
Strategy meeting
Sound confident
Emphasize everyone's role
Pumpkin
Radio broadcast
Strategy meeting
Sound confident
Emphasize everyone's role
Pumpkin
Radio broadcast
Strategy meeting
Sound confident
Emphasize everyone's role
Pumpkin
Radio broadcast
Strategy meeting
Sound confident
Emphasize everyone's role
Pumpkin
Radio broadcast
Strategy meeting
Sound confident
Emphasize everyone's role
Pumpkin
Radio broadcast
Strategy meeting
Sound confident
Emphasize everyone's role
Pumpkin
Radio broadcast
Strategy meeting
Sound confident
Emphasize everyone's role
Pumpkin
Radio broadcast
Strategy meeting
Sound confident
Emphasize everyone's role
Pumpkin
Radio broadcast
Strategy meeting
Sound confident
Emphasize everyone's role
Pumpkin
With everyone's help, I'm sure we'll be able to catch Juumoji!
Radio broadcast
Strategy meeting
Sound confident
Emphasize everyone's role
Pumpkin
Radio broadcast
Strategy meeting
Sound confident
Emphasize everyone's role
Pumpkin
Radio broadcast
Strategy meeting
Sound confident
Emphasize everyone's role
Pumpkin
千反田さん　ご健闘を
ありがとうございます
Full of confidence, I see!
皆さん　応援してください
Which brings us to: What do you think Juumoji will steal next?
千反田愛瑠さんでした
We've prepared just the thing!
はい　OKです
The Classics Club has some copy papers for just this occasion.
Copy papers?
なかなかよかったよ
Yes, the copy papers we use for our anthology, Hyouka.
ありがとうございます
どうしたんだい
Huh? There's less?
いいえ　本当にこれでよかったのかなあっと
Target: Sell all 2OO copies!
114 sold
Our anthology features a story that's just as exciting as the Juumoji incident,
On air
so please take a look at it if you get the chance!
I think you'll all enjoy it!
Advertise Hyouka
Pumpkin
Wow! We'll be thinking about that one for a while!
I hope you'll all check out the Classics Club's anthology, Hyouka!
@ 湮·Molly／小然·酸菜／喵儿·小冷／时末·竭力而为
KamiGami
複雑に構えた今日が 息を呑んで澄ましてる
I'm sure you'll like it!
By the way, while we wait for Juumoji to pay us a visit,
身に覚えあるだろう 君はどうしたい
there's something those of us in the Classics Club need your help with.
You need help?
Yes. There's only four of us, so we can't really keep a thorough watch.
何もなかったそぶりで  かばう痛みはもう
That's why I'd like to ask you all to come to the Classics Club!
心強いくらいに 急かすんだ
You're our only hope!
I see! The more people watching, the more they'll see!
掴んでこぼして 不完全な僕たちが
Yes! We're counting on your help!
光って見えない 未来の自分を創れるなら
How could let a young lady's pleas fall on deaf ears?
And, if you could...
Please buy our anthology too... Okay?
目覚めるまま走れ 蜃気楼を追い越して
The final target, the Classics Club, stands ready to intercept the thief!
変わりたいまま走れ 自由な違和感で
Chitanda, we wish you luck!
Thank you! I hope you'll all support us!
届きそうな輝きと今を選んでいこう
And that was Chitanda Eru!
That's a wrap!
飛びたつ手を知らない
That was pretty good!
深い 浅い 呼吸を重ねて
Thank you very much.
What's wrong?
Hyouka
I was just wondering if it really was good enough...
Kudryavka's Order
库特莉亚芙卡的顺序
Juumoji vs The Classics Club
I'll take one.
ください
That'll be 200 yen.
200円です
This, please.
ください
That'll be 200 yen.
200円です
Please.
ください
おー　売れる　売れるぞ
Whoa! They really are selling!
Almost there! We've nearly sold them all!
もうすぐだ　もうすぐ完売する
Is he really gonna turn up?
本当に来るのか
At this point, what can he even do?
こんな囲まれてちゃ手出しなんてできないよね～
Yeah, he's got no chance.
本当本当　もう無理じゃない
How long's he gonna make us wait?
いつまで待たせんだよ　ったく
Does Juumoji even exist?
十文字って本当にいるの？
実は自作自演とか
What if they made it all up?
I can totally imagine that!
そりゃあり得る
いい加減出てこいよな
I'm getting fed up with this...
Sorry, that's just my phone.
ごめん　それ　僕の携帯
You're not going to answer?
もう
出なくても？
Nah, it's just—
ああ　警備が終わったら…
They're burning! They're burning!
おい　燃えてる　燃えてるぞ！
消せ　消せ
Put it out!
Water?
水？
We got hit.
やられた
うそ　なんで？
Take a look at this.
ちょっと　これ
びっくりした
The Classics Club has lost its copy papers.
The ten letters are complete.
Juumoji
The Classics Club has lost its copy papers.
The ten letters are complete.
Juumoji
The Classics Club has lost its copy papers.
The ten letters are complete.
Juumoji
The Classics Club has lost its copy papers.
The ten letters are complete.
Juumoji
The Classics Club has lost its copy papers.
The ten letters are complete.
Juumoji
The Classics Club has lost its copy papers.
The ten letters are complete.
Juumoji
The Classics Club has lost its copy papers.
The ten letters are complete.
Juumoji
The Classics Club has lost its copy papers.
The ten letters are complete.
Juumoji
The Classics Club has lost its copy papers.
The ten letters are complete.
Juumoji
Juumoji's calling card.
十文字の犯行声明だ
だから言っただろ
お前　本当にわかってたのかよ
Did you really know?
やってくれるな
You know, I was thinking that Juumoji might be a girl.
十文字ってさ　私が思うにはきっと女の子じゃないかなあって
どうして？
Classics Club Defeated
They sold out.
完売だ
定価で売ってやりたかったがな
Would you have preferred to sell them at full price?
No! This is more than enough!
いいえ　そんな　十分です
Just... Thank you very much!
本当に　本当に　ありがとうございました
Stop it.
止めろ
And also...
それからだが…
Yes?
はい？
I guess I should tell you.
やはり言っておくべきか
What?
何でしょうか
I heard you on the radio show.
校内放送を聞いたぞ
Really? Thanks to your advice, I—
ええ　入須さんのアドバイスのお陰で
Yeah, it's about that.
それなんだが　私も考えが浅かった
I didn't think this through all the way.
I'll make this clear:
はっきり言っておこう
You are ill-suited to manipulating people in this way.
お前にはああいうのは向かない
お前がああやって期待を操ろうとすると
When you try to do it, you just come across as demanding attention.
どうにも甘えているように聞こえる
Demanding attention?
甘えている…　そんな風に聞こえましたか
Is that really how it sounds?
小指の先ほどだがな
Only a little. A mere fingernail's worth.
But as it happens, if you keep up such an act for too long,
しかし　フリで続けていたことが
you may find, in the end, that it becomes the real you.
いつしか本心にすり替るなんてよくあることだ
Okay.
はい
What I'm getting at is, don't base everything you do on my advice.
私の話を真に受けて　下手に画策するのだけは止めた方がいい
You might consider it a weakness that you can't help but be straightforward,
単刀直入な言い方しかできないのはお前の弱点だが
but at the same time it's also a rare and powerful weapon.
ほかでは得難い武器でもある
Do you understand?
その…　分かるか
Yes. I was thinking the same thing.
ええ　私も思っていました
Pretending to be someone else really doesn't fit me.
こういうことはまるで私向きじゃありません
I guess, to put it simply...
えと　つまりですね
I've had enough of it.
もう　懲り懲りです
いやー　お前でも十文字は捕まえられなかったか
So in the end, not even you could catch Juumoji.
Closing Ceremony
Acting Troupe
Marching Band
End of Festival
Closing Ceremony
Marching Band
End of Festival
Acting Troupe
Closing Ceremony
Marching Band
End of Festival
I expected more of you.
期待してたんだかなー
Oh well. I do regret that we couldn't live up to your expectations.
まあね　どうもご期待にそえなかったようで
All the same, this culture fair sure was a lot of fun.
いやまあ　なかなか楽しい文化祭だったよ
I'll pay you back for the cooking thing one day.
料理の借りはまたいつか返すぞ
See you around!
それじゃ
Who's that?
誰？
Tani.
谷君
He sucks at Japanese, I guess.
国語の苦手な人　かな
Where'd that come from?
何それ
He uses the word "expectation" much too easily.
どうも　彼はね
期待って言葉を軽々しく使いすぎる
Does it matter? There's no rule against—
別にいいじゃない　期待なんて…
People who are confident in themselves never talk about expectations.
自分に自信がある時は期待なんて言葉を出しちゃいけない
期待っていうのは諦めから出る言葉なんだよ
"Expectation" is a word rooted in giving up.
そうせざるを得ない　どうしようもなさがないと　空々しいよ
It leaves you with no other choice. It makes it obvious that you're powerless.
福ちゃん
Fuku...
Speaking of expectations...
期待っていうのは例えば
Houtarou should be around here.
奉太郎　確かこっちの方に…
There!
いた
単刀直入に行きましょう
Let's get straight to the point.
You are Juumoji, aren't you, Tanabe?
あなたが十文字ですね
田名辺先輩
Are you just guessing?
あてっずっぽうかな
No, I have my reasons.
いいえ　証拠があります
田名辺先輩が
Tanabe?
First of all, these cards.
まずこのカード
Why do they say "lost" and not "stolen"?
なぜ「盗まれた」ではなく　「失われた」なのか
lost
Who knows?
さあ
The next issue is "ku". That letter was skipped.
次の問題は「く」です
「く」は飛ばされた
That alone pokes a hole in Juumoji's pattern.
これだけで十文字の法則は崩壊です
But what if there was something beginning with "ku" that we didn't consider?
だが　俺らの知らないところで「く」に纏わる何かがあったとしたら
Such as?
というと？
十文字事件とは　それ自体が暗号だったんじゃないですか
Wasn't the whole Juumoji incident in itself a code?
The whole thing was designed to convey one message:
「く」で始まる相手に「く」で始まるものが
that someone beginning with "ku" had already lost something beginning with "ku".
すでに失われているというメッセージを伝えるための
That's quite a difficult code.
ずいぶん難しい暗号だね
Impossible to break, even.
普通は解けません
Unless you know how to decode it.
ところが　もしその相手が解読法を知っていたとしたら
Let me say this straight:
言ってしまいますとね
I think that was the plot of Kudryavka's Order.
俺は　それこそが
「クドリャフカの順番」の筋立てだったと思ってるんですよ
You're wondering how I knew that title?
「なぜその題名を知っている」と思っているんでしょう
Kudryavka's Order is a twist on Christie's famous book, The ABC Murders.
「クドリャフカの順番」はクリスティーの超有名作
「ABC殺人事件」を捻ったものです
In the Juumoji incident, the culprit focused on Kudryavka's Order.
そして　十文字事件も
犯人のネタ文は「クドリャフカの順番」です
That is to say, the recipient of the code. Someone beginning with "ku"...
そして暗号を受け取る側
「く」のつく相手とは陸山宗芳
Kugayama Muneyoshi, the student council president.
生徒会会長
The illustrator for Dead at Dusk.
「夕べには骸に」の作画担当
Am I wrong?
違いますか
But if every other target was a club, why would he target a person for "ku"?
ほかはみんな部活なのに
「く」だけ人名というのはいただけないな
Juumoji never said he was only targeting the clubs.
十文字は何も部活だけを襲うとは書いていない
You're trying so hard.
苦しいね
Not at all.
苦しくはないですよ
You gave us the list of potential targets.
あなたはちゃんとターゲットはこの中から選ぶというリスト
提示していました
You didn't just copy the order from the ABC Schedule.
「ABC時刻表」の真似をしたなんてことじゃない
The schedule itself is the list of victims.
これこそが被害者リストだったんです
All the victims were chosen from these pages.
被害者はすべてこのページから選ばれている
A Capella Choir. Go Club. Fortune Teller Club.
アカペラ部　囲碁部　占い研
Gardening Club. Cooking Lab. News Poster Club. Magic Club.
園芸部　お料理研　壁新聞部　奇術部
And then, Kugayama Muneyoshi.
そして　陸山宗芳
Kugayama Muneyoshi
If someone figured all that out, it wouldn't be hard to find you.
これが分かれば
あなたに辿り着くのはそう難しくない
It'd be too much of a coincidence that all the victims ended up being on this page.
このページにたまたま被害者が固まったというのは
できすぎでしょう
But who has control over the contents? Only the General Affairs people.
そしてページを操作できるの総務委員会の誰かだ
But there are 20 people on the General Affairs Committee.
だが　総務委員は20人いる
Yes. That's where this manga, Dead at Dusk, comes into the picture.
ええ
そこでこの漫画　「夕べには骸に」です
President Kugayama worked on this with the author, Anjou Haruna,
これの原作者　安城春菜と組んでいた陸山会長は
so he must've known about Kudryavka's Order as well.
「クドリャフカの順番」のことも知っていたはず
Which means President Kugayama would be able to decode Juumoji's message.
つまり
十文字事件の暗号　陸山会長は解くことができるわけです
I'm just guessing, but maybe he lost the script for Kudryavka's Order?
これは一つの仮定だが
陸山会長は「クドリャフカの順番」の原作を紛失してしまったのでは？
Maybe Juumoji caused this scandal to condemn him for that.
その批判として　十文字はこの事件を起こしたのではないか
Which means the culprit's message was this:
つまり犯人からのメッセージはこうです
"Kugayama has lost Kudryavka's Order."
陸山から「クドリャフカの順番」はすでに失われた
Finally, the afterword.
そして　この後書き
It was written by the person who helped draw the backgrounds.
背景を手伝った人間が書いたものだ
Anjou Haruna. President Kugayama.
安城春菜　陸山会長
He was the only one beside those two who knew about Kudryavka's Order.
それ以外で「クドリャフカの順番」の原作を知っている唯一の人間
Therefore, he's the only possible candidate for Juumoji.
この人だけが十文字たり得る
Then there's this.
そしてこれです
Ajimu Takuha. What a strange pen name.
「安心院鐸玻」　妙なペンネームです
It's made from the first syllable of each of the authors' names.
これはこの作品を書いた三人の名前の頭文字を
並べ書いたものですね
So?
というと？
Ajimu    Takuha
Anjou
Haruna
Anjou Haruna: "a" and "ha".
安城春菜　「あ」と「は」
Ajimu    Takuha
Ajimu    TakuHa
Kugayama Muneyoshi: "ku" and "mu".
Kugayama
Muneyoshi
陸山宗芳　「く」と「む」
AjiMu    Takuha
Ajimu    TaKuha
Ajimu    Takuha
AjiMu    Takuha
Ajimu    TaKuha
If you subtract those from Ajimu Takuha,
これを「あじむたくは」から引いてみると
you're left with the two syllables of "ji" and "ta".
残る二文字は「じ」と「た」になります
Ajimu    Takuha
Ajimu    takuha
Someone who was around for last year's fair, so at least a second-year,
去年も文化祭に参加できた二年生以上で総務委員
a member of the General Affairs Committee,
and someone whose initials are "ta" and "ji".
苗字と名前に「た」と「じ」がつく人物
Furthermore, they would have to be close to President Kugayama
加えて陸山会長と親しく　彼が漫画を描けると知っている者
and know that he was making a manga.
そんな人間は一人しかいない
There's only one such person.
あなたですよ
And that would be you,
Tanabe Jirou.
田名辺治郎先輩
見事だ
Well done.
I didn't think anyone but Mune and Anjou would be able to figure it out.
まさか　宗と安城さん以外に読み解けるやつがいるなんて
思いもしなかった
Seriously, you outdid my expectations, Houtarou.
まったく
期待以上だよ　奉太郎
秋分
阴阳相半也
Autumn Equinox
When light and dark are in balance.
Hyouka
The Cooking Lab has lost their ladle.
Juumoji
Why did you use such a roundabout code?
どうしてこんな回りくどい暗号を使ったんです？
You've got some idea, haven't you?
うすうす分かっちゃいるんだろ？
Is it to do with your feelings for Anjou Haruna, who transferred?
転校していった安城春菜への思いってところですか
ははは　それもあった
Yeah, that too.
Plus, I wanted to pull a grand prank for the culture fair.
それと　せっかくの文化祭だから
悪戯を仕掛けたかったっていう気持ちもね
But...
けど
It was mostly because I couldn't say it myself.
「口で言えなかったから」が一番大きいかな
Very well. There's something I'd like to discuss.
さて　そこで物は相談です
I have a request for you, Tanabe.
田名辺先輩にしてほしいことがあるんですよ
What is it?
というと？
Please purchase these.
これを買っていただきたい
Our anthology, Hyouka. 30 copies, all up.
文集「氷菓」　しめて30部
You want me to buy my anonymity with those?
正体をばらさない代わりにそれを買えと？
Yes.
ええ
Though, the General Affairs Committee would be the ones buying them.
ただし買うのは総務委員会です
That's impossible!
ばかな
It's not impossible.
ばかなことじゃありません
Haven't you been selling various items off the culture fair website?
神山高校のサイト
文化祭で出品されたものを通販してるじゃないですか
You can simply buy them and put them up for sale there.
総務委員会がいったん買い上げ
それをサイトで売る形にしてもらえればいいんです
I can't just buy them without a reason.
理由もなく買い上げることはできない
They'd need to be a popular item that people are talking about.
せめで何かの話題になってなければ
Precisely.
ごもっとも
But people will be talking about Hyouka.
しかし話題になるんですよ　この「氷菓」は
What do you mean?
どういうことかな
The Juumoji incident, of course.
もちろん十文字事件ですよ
The Classics Club will be the final target.
古典部を最後の標的にするんです
I'll help you, and I'll get Fukube Satoshi in on this as well.
俺と　それから福部里志にでも頼んで
犯行をサポートします
With insiders at your target,
ターゲットに内通者ができるんです
nothing could be easier.
こんな簡単な話はありません
People will flock to the Classics Club out of curiosity,
十文字の最後のターゲット古典部には
やじ馬が押しかける
and sales of the anthology will rise as a result.
文集も数はでるでしょう
That should be enough reason to stock it on the website.
となれば通販で引き受ける理由にもなる
And you can complete the sequence of thefts cleanly and without issues.
そして先輩は事件をきっちり終わらせるって寸法です
What do you say?
どうですか
That...
確かに
sounds quite good.
悪い話じゃないな
We'll bring the Juumoji case to a close,
十文字事件の完結
and our online store will get something new in stock.
通販商品の充実
Our goals coincide.
利害は一致しているな
Good to hear.
よかったです
で　どう十文字をサポートしてくれるのかな
And how do you plan to assist Juumoji?
We'll get some copy papers ready as the target item.
標的として校了原稿を用意します
It'll be guarded so closely that no one could even get near it.
そこに誰も近づけないように見張りを立てます
Oh? So?
ほー　それで？
According to this,
このシオリによれば
the Chemistry Lab will be demonstrating the effects of mixing sodium with water.
化学部がナトリウムに水をかけたときの反応を実演しているそうです
I've seen it in documentaries before. It reacts quite spectacularly.
前に何かの動画で見たんですが
結構派手に燃えてくれます
あっ　まさかそのナトリウムを？
You're planning to use sodium?
Yes. Please get some any way you can.
ええ　なんとかして入手してください
I also believe that someone at the Candy Club has a water pistol shaped like a handgun.
それから製菓研で拳銃型の水鉄砲を持ってる連中がいます
Please arrange to borrow it from them.
これも交渉して手に入れてください
You're planning something dangerous.
危ないことを考えるなあ
It's a festival. Time for some fireworks.
お祭りです　最後は派手に行きましょう
Oh boy.
やれやれ
I'll find a way to hide the sodium between the pages of the copy papers.
俺がなんとかして校了原稿のページの間に
ナトリウムを挟んでおきます
When we've sold enough copies, I'll signal you like this.
本が十分売れたら
こんな感じの合図をするんで
When you see that, shoot the water pistol.
水鉄砲で原稿を撃ってください
Everyone will be watching the papers, though.
だが　みんなの目が原稿に集まっているはずだろ？
That's right.
そうですね
Then we'll put Satoshi's smartphone near the entrance of the room.
では　部屋の入口近くに里志のスマホを置いていきます
Before you shoot, give him a call.
水をかける前に電話をしてください
The ringing phone will draw attention away from the papers.
観客の注意はそちらに向くでしょう
Got it. What about Juumoji's calling card?
分かった
犯行声明はどうする？
The place will be in an uproar.
現場は混乱するでしょうから
You can just hide it in a copy of Hyouka and drop it on the floor.
「氷菓」に挟んで床にでも落としてください
Very well.
いいだろう
Then please purchase said copy.
じゃあ　それ用の「氷菓」を買ってもらいます
That'll be 200 yen.
一冊二百円
You never miss an opportunity.
ちゃっかりしてるな
Desperate times call for desperate measures.
心底困ってるんですよ　俺たち
What was your name again?
君　名前はなんだったかな
Oreki Houtarou, from class 1-B.
一年Ｂ組　折木奉太郎です
You mean expectations, like the ones you have for Houtarou?
期待っていうのは福ちゃんが折木に思っているようなこと？
That's right. How did you know?
お見事　どうして分かった？
I can tell just by looking at you. It's you, after all.
見てれば分かるわよ　福ちゃんのことくらい
You wanted to beat Oreki?
福ちゃんは折木に勝ちたかったの？
It's not that I wanted to beat him. He's not better than me in every way.
勝ちたいわけじゃなかったけど
見上げてばかりじゃね
まあ　こればっかりは摩耶花にも分からないだろうね
But I guess you wouldn't understand.
You guessed wrong.
そんなことない
Well, I've been careless.
僕もうっかりしてたよ
I forgot one important thing:
こいつを忘れちゃいけなかった
A database can't draw conclusions.
データベースは結論を出せないんだ
54th Kamiyama High School Culture Fair
I'm pleased to announce that this year's Kan'ya Fair reached its end without trouble.
ええ　今年のカンヤ祭もつつがなく終えることができました
Closing Ceremony
Though, I believe there were a few strange incidents here and there.
いや　なんか変な事件もあったみたいだけど
Nice job!
お疲れ
Anyway, it's all over now!
えー　とにかくお疲れ
As of this moment, the 54th Kamiyama High School Culture Fair is concluded!
ここに　第五十四回神山高校文化祭の閉幕を宣言します
気をつけろよ
OK
I may be a bit late, but I've finally got it.
遅くなりましたけど　持ってきました
I believe that this manga's author could write a great masterpiece one day.
私がいつか名作を書けると信じている人の漫画を
You really had it?
本当に持っていたんだね
はい　これは借り物ですけど
Yes. I just borrowed this one, though.
You knew about this manga, right?
先輩は　この漫画のこと知ってたんですね
Yuasa couldn't keep her mouth shut, huh?
湯浅か　あいつ…
You were friends with the author of this manga, right?
河内先輩とこの漫画の原作の人は友達だったって
Friends? Yeah, I guess.
友達　そうね
I hope Haruna's doing all right. Haven't heard from her for ages.
春菜元気でやってるかなあ
長いこと声も聞いていないけど
Have you read this manga?
この漫画読んだんですか
I kind of understand where you were coming from.
私　河内先輩の言うことも少し分かります
That "good" and "bad" are in the end subjective definitions.
面白いかどうかは結局主観の問題だっていうこと
But I still can't accept that as the truth!
でも　やっぱりそれが正しいとは思えません
If that's true, then what's the point?
だって　それってあまりにも虚しいじゃないですか
Is that why you brought up Dead at Dusk?
だから「夕べには骸に」なんだね
But that's a serious story.
でも　それシリアスでしょ？
If I were a comedy buff, I wouldn't even read it.
もしあたしがギャグ専門だったら読みもしない
That's what I meant.
そういうことじゃない？
If you read it, you'd understand! I'm positive!
読めば分かる　絶対に
There are stories that have the power to appeal to everyone!
そういう力を持った作品だってあるんです
Only if you're someone who knows the difference.
違いの分かる人には　でしょ？
Kouchi!
河内先輩！
I'm kidding.
冗談よ
冗談
Did you think I seriously believed that?
そんなこと　本気で言ってるわけないじゃない
You have no sense of humor, Ibara.
冗談が通じないね　伊原ってさ
I don't think Ayako really meant it.
亜也子はね　本気じゃないのよ
I can't get away from it, can I?
逃げ切れないもんだね
I never finished reading that manga.
私　それ読んでないんだ
I stopped midway.
途中でやめた
Do you know why?
なんでか分かる？
No...
いいえ
You said if I read it, I'd understand.
あんた「読めば分かる」　そう言ったよね
I really did. I really started to understand.
そう　分かるよ　分かっちゃうんだ
But I don't want to admit that.
でも　ほら　そういうって認めたくないでしょ？
What about you?
あんたならどうよ
If you had a friend who didn't even read manga, as far as you knew...
あんまり漫画読まないねって思ってた友達がさ
If she made an original script...
初めての原作ってさ　それを書いたとしたらさ
You know, if she wrote it...
ねえ　洒落にならないと思うでしょう
You'd think it couldn't possibly be any good, right?
So it's in my closet, buried inside a box at the very back.
だからそれは押入れの奥　一番奥の箱の中
I pretended I couldn't see it and that there was no such thing as a true classic.
見ないことにして
ついでに名作なんてどこにもないことにしてたのにね
What a crazy twist of fate.
つくづく巡り合わせだね
You must've gone through some trouble to get that,
せっかく手に入れたのに悪いけど
but sorry, I'm not gonna read it.
あたしそれ読まないから
You know, if I'd read it, I'd have ended up calling her...
だってさ　ほら
読んじゃったら電話しちゃうじゃない
But even if I had called her, you know...
でも電話してさ
I can't just say, "Hey, you're amazing! I'm looking forward to your next one!"
「読んだよ　あんたすごいじゃない　次のも期待してるね」とか
...Can I?
言えないじゃない　ねえ
That's from Body Talk...
これ　「ボディトーク」の…
Truly exceptional manga have been exceptional since the beginning!
名作は最初から名作として生まれてくるんです
Body Talk. Yeah, this'll do.
「ボディトーク」　やっぱりこれもいい
Mine don't hold a candle to either.
私のは百枚落ちる
Are these all that are left?
残りはこれだけですか
Yeah.
ああ
おお！　ここまで…　ここまで来るとは！
We've... We've come so far!
Amazing! We moved that mountain of anthologies, stone by stone!
すごいです
あの文集の山が… 期待以上の大戦果です
This is a bigger success than I ever expected!
Expectations...
期待…
Expectations, huh?
期待ね
ああ
いや
I can't tell Chitanda I sold them through blackmail.
恐喝して押し売りしたなんて　千反田には言えんな
Oreki!
折木君
You said I planned this incident because Kugayama lost the manuscript for Kudryavka's Order.
君は　陸山が「クドリャフカの順番」の原作を紛失したから
僕がこういう事件を起こしたと言ったね
That was just a guess. I have no clues as to your motives.
あくまで仮定です
先輩の動機までは知りようがありませんから
No surprises there.
まあ　無理もない
I guess only Anjou could understand my feelings.
僕の気持ちが分かるのは多分安城さんだけだ
Not President Kugayama?
陸山会長には分からないと？
Yeah.
ああ
But the code was meant for President Kugayama, right?
陸山会長にあてた暗号なんですよね
Yes.
そうだよ
Then why?
だったら　なぜ？
Mune... Kugayama hasn't picked up a pen since we finished Dead at Dusk.
宗は…　陸山は「夕べには骸に」を仕上げて以来
一度もペンを握ってないんだ
Anjou is a genius, but I didn't know Mune could draw so well.
安城さんも天才的だけと
宗があれほど書けるとは知らなかった
I pale in comparison to him.
下手くそな僕とは比べものにならない
The manuscript has been there all along! It's not lost!
原作はちゃんとあるんだ　なくしてなんかない！
If he felt like it, he could make something even greater than Dead at Dusk!
あいつがその気になりさえすれば
「夕べには骸に」を超える話にだってなるはずなんだ！
But for Mune, drawing manga was just a one-off thing he did for fun.
けど　宗にとって漫画描きは
あの時限りの遊びだったんだ
That was just "fun"?
あれが…遊び
It's a waste, isn't it? A shame, right?
もったいないだろ？　惜しいと思うだろ？
But Mune doesn't draw anymore.
なのに宗は描こうとしない
All he had to say was, "Let's do it!" and I'd do anything to make it happen.
あいつが一言やるぞって言えば
僕は何でもするつもりでいた
But I was too scared to ask him.
宗に聞くのが怖かった
I didn't want to believe he might not notice my message.
メッセージに気づかないなんて信じたくなかった
From desperate differences, expectations are born.
絶望的な差からは期待が生まれる
I've had expectations all along.
僕はずっと期待していた
Then your true message was...
なら　あなたが本当に伝えたかったことはこうですか
"Kugayama, have you read Kudryavka's Order?"
陸山　お前は「クドリャフカの順番」を読んだのか
Very well done.
本当に見事だ
And his answer was?
そして答えは
Oh, that's right.
ああ　そうだ
Mune hasn't even opened the manuscript that Anjou put all her effort into.
宗は
安城さん渾身の原作を開いてもなかった
The code wasn't broken.
暗号は解かれなかった
He never received my message.
メッセージは伝わらなかったよ
Oreki, thanks for letting me borrow this!
折木　これ　ありがとう
Say thanks to your sister too, please.
お姉さんにもお礼言っといて
Sure.
ああ
What?
なによ
Don't worry, I'll tell her.
いや　伝えておくるよ
What should we do about these four?
じゃあ　この残った四部はどうしましょうか
Now that we're not gonna sell these anymore,
残ってもしかたないし
why don't we all buy one more each?
全員でもう一部ずつ買うってことで
これで　完売です！
And now we've sold them all!
Hooray!
やったー
Now all that's left is the Juumoji incident!
後は　十文字事件の真相ですね
With nothing else to worry about, we can start thinking about it full-time!
これで　心置きなく気にすることができます！
Um... Actually...
あっ　いや
ああ　それなら奉太郎がちょっと分かったことがあるみたいだよ
Actually, Houtarou managed to find out a few things about it.
Really? Oreki!
本当ですか
折木さん
Oh well...
いや　それは…
We can talk about all that later,
その辺の話も含めて　どうかな
so how about we go out to celebrate selling our entire stock of Hyouka?
完売祝いに打ち上げと行かないかい
おおー
Satoshi!
里志！
Bear with me for this, at least.
これくらいは許してもらわないとね
はあ？
I'm for celebrating!
打ち上げ賛成
I barely got to spend any time at the Classics Club,
古典部にはほとんど出られなかったし
so I'd like to hear all your stories!
いろいろ話を聞かせてよ
Then why don't we go to my house?
では　私の家にいらっしゃいませんか
It's decided!
よし　決まり
It is?
決まったのか
Okay! Let's drink ourselves silly!
よし　憂さ晴らしだ　今日は飲むわよ
You drink?
飲むのか
All the time! Mostly oolong tea!
主にウーロン茶
なんだ　そのフォロー
Was that supposed to be a joke?
Sold out!
Next time: Does the Sun Shine on the Peaks?
Does the Sun Shine on the Peaks?
状況は非科学的に 感情のモンタージュ
誰が誰を呼んでる
振り向けば逃げてく視線（感じる）
気のせいじゃつれないよ アンテナは才能って言うでしょ
だって（だって） 知りたい（君は違うの？）
青春の温度差 今のうち正してあげるよ
明日解決するなら 今でもよくない？
君のミステリー解いてみたい
少年の秘密めいた背中探せ（今日も）
君はファンタジー 惹かれてゆくよ（ずるい）
膨らんだ好奇心 とりたくはないのに
気になるよ 興味深い どうして
次回　連峰は晴れているか